Guide to the Max Wilk Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- May 2004 Acquisition, 1881-2001; 35; 31.35; (48 boxes) + 1 record album storage
  - "A Very Early American," film story, 1985 (Box 82)
  - "Yellow Submarine", 1988 March 1 (Box 82)
  - "Show Business Applauds Lincoln Center", 1986-1987; 3 (Box 82)
  - Remembering Schwab's variety, 1984 (Box 82)
  - "A Tough Act to Follow," how to do it on TV, 1986 (Box 82)
  - "It's Only Money," film, 1988 (Box 82)
  - "Friends and Neighbors," proposal for CBS TV, 1983-1985 (Box 82)
  - "Mr. Williams and Miss Wood", 1989 (Box 82)
  - "Mr. Williams and Miss Wood," early drafts, 1979-1980; 2 (Box 82)
  - "These Are the Jokes", 1987, undated; 3 (Box 82)
  - "Santa Fe Story", 1986-1987 (Box 82)
  - Odds and ends of the 2000 era, 1971-2001 (Box 82)
  - Navajo reservation, Grey Hills School 52nd street project, 1993 (Box 82)
  - Sack, Harold: material for book, 1984-1987; 2 (Box 82)
  - "Harold Sack", 1985 March 29 (Box 83)
  - "Harold Sack," manuscript, 1985; 2 (Box 83)
  - "Harold Sack", 1982-1984 (Box 83)
  - Sack manuscript, 1985 June (Box 83)
  - "Harold Sack," tape #1: transcript from a recording, 1984 September 24 (Box 83)
  - "Harold Sack," tape #2: transcript from a recording, 1984 October 4 (Box 83)
  - "Harold Sack," tape #3: transcript from a recording, 1984 October 8 (Box 83)
  - "Harold Sack," lecture of fakes, (tape #4): transcript from a recording, 1984 October 28 (Box 83)
  - Harold S. - a: Ima Hogg, b: Maxim Karouk, 1985 February (Box 83)
  - Gustav Klimt, an exhibition of drawings, 1979 (Box 83)
  - "Hallie Flanagan", undated (Box 83)
  - Untitled manuscript, undated; 5 (Box 83)
  - "Feather in Your Cap", 1982; 3 (Box 83)
  - Autobiography, undated (Box 83)
  - "Is it Okay to Plant a Pickle?," "Is it Okay to Plant a Pretzel?," "Growing Pains", 1981 (Box 83)
  - Hayward outline, 1976 (Box 83)
  - "They Said It With Music", 1976 (Box 83)
  - "My Masterpiece," screenplay, 1978 July (Box 83)
  - "Test Pattern", undated (Box 83)
  - "Live From New York", 1982; 2 (Box 83)
  - "Live From New York," outline, 1981 (Box 83)
  - Yale Repertory Theatre stage production programs, 1984-2001; 2 (Box 84)
  - Long Wharf Theatre stage production programs, 1985-2001; 4 (Box 84)
  - Stage production programs, 1972-2002; 9 (Box 84)
  - "Reach for the Sky", undated; 2 (Box 85)
  - "Three Cheers for Uncle Eddie", undated; 2 (Box 85)
  - "Hands Across the Sea", 1954 (Box 85)
  - "Sit Back and Relax", undated (Box 85)
  - "Fatal Slip Up", undated (Box 85)
  - "Mary, Irving and the 22 Waist", undated (Box 85)
  - Pipe Dream stage production program, 1955 (Box 85)
  - South Pacific stage production program, 1948-1949 (Box 85)
  - My Fair Lady stage production program, 1956 (Box 85)
  - "The Man Who Bought a Town", undated (Box 85)
  - Oh Dad, Poor Dad stage production program, Westport Country Playhouse, 1963 (Box 85)
  - "Ghost of a Rider", 1956 (Box 85)
  - "In Strangest America" outline and correspondence, 1956 (Box 85)
  - "The Bride Wore a Muzzle", 1957 (Box 85)
  - "Twenty Four Hundred Knives", 1956 (Box 85)
  - Unidentified List, undated (Box 85)
  - "Be a Clown", 1954 (Box 85)
  - "Golden Summer", 1950 (Box 85)
  - "Come Love, Let Us Fly", 1954 (Box 85)
  - Literary properties owned by Max Wilk, 1953 November (Box 85)
  - "Mrs Jackson's Jewel", 1954 (Box 85)
  - "Kings and How to Know Them", undated (Box 85)
  - "Rotten Book" etc..., 1986-1989, undated (Box 85)
  - Notepad, 1958 (Box 85)
  - Partial list of material, undated (Box 85)
  - "The Tunnel of Love", 1955, undated; 3 (Box 85)
  - "Ask Me No Questions", undated (Box 85)
  - "They're Coming through the Window", 1953 (Box 85)
  - "Everybody Wants My Wife", undated (Box 85)
  - "Red Letter Day", 1953 (Box 85)
  - "The Man With All the Answers", 1955; 5 (Box 85)
  - "The Double Take", 1954 (Box 85)
  - Variety tribute to Rodgers and Hammerstein's Oklahoma! et al, 1993 March 29 (Box 85)
  - List of works, undated; 2 (Box 86)
  - List of box contents, undated (Box 86)
  - 50th Anniversary of Oklahoma!, 1993; 4 (Box 86)
  - "A Very Remarkable Woman," Philco Playhouse, 1951 November 4; 2 (Box 86)
  - "A Very Remarkable Woman", 1952; 2 (Box 86)
  - Outlines (Mr. Kirsch), undated (Box 86)
  - Dr. Van Waters ideas: " Brass Section," notes, 1951 (Box 86)
  - "The Dorothy Shay Show", undated (Box 86)
  - "The Uppers and the Lowers", 1956 (Box 86)
  - "The Butler Did It", 1953 (Box 86)
  - "The Writing on the Wall", 1955 (Box 86)
  - "Meet Me Tonight in Birdland", undated (Box 86)
  - "The Cutting Edge", undated (Box 86)
  - Miscellaneous scripts, 1948-1949 (Box 86)
  - "Don't Tread on Me", 1975 (Box 86)
  - "The British Are Coming", undated (Box 86)
  - "The Little Woman", 1966 (Box 86)
  - Yale Literary Magazine 2 copies, 1939 November; 2 (Box 86)
  - Yale Literary Magazine, 1939 May (Box 86)
  - Yale Literary Magazine, 1940 January (Box 86)
  - "Little Lost Sheep", 1941 November; 2 (Box 86)
  - "The Listeners' Theatre", 1940-1941; 2 (Box 86)
  - "Look Out for Number One", 1970 (Box 86)
  - "The Staff Hippy", undated (Box 86)
  - "A Dirty Mind Never Sleeps", undated (Box 86)
  - Literature and Reality by Howard Fast, 1950 (Box 86)
  - The Animal Kingdom by Phillip Barry, 1931 (Box 86)
  - "Live from New York", 1981; 4 (Box 87)
  - "Live from New York", 1982; 3 (Box 87)
  - "Redskin Redskin Why Are You Blue?", undated; 2 (Box 87)
  - "When Television Was Young", 1977 April 28 (Box 87)
  - "Type A", 1991; 2 (Box 87)
  - "Beautiful Morning", 1991 (Box 87)
  - "From Yankee Doodle To Ragtime" CBS-TV, 1975 (Box 87)
  - "Tea and Wine at 103 Frognal", 1980 (Box 87)
  - Novel notes, 1983-1984 (Box 87)
  - "The Joy of Stress", 1984 (Box 87)
  - "Home" TV pilot, 1984 March (Box 87)
  - "Larry," "Nobody's Heart", 1998, undated (Box 87)
  - "Nobody's Heart", undated (Box 87)
  - God of Small Things, undated (Box 88)
  - The Sound of Music: The Making of America's Favorite Movie, undated (Box 88)
  - Unidentified notes, undated (Box 88)
  - Photographic negatives from an unidentified production of The Sound of Music, 1998 (Box 88)
  - Goodman, Frank, notes, 1996 October 7 (Box 88)
  - Bikel quotes, undated (Box 88)
  - Letter from Saul Chaplin, undated (Box 88)
  - Chaplin book, undated (Box 88)
  - Morden, Ethan, notes, undated (Box 88)
  - TV in the 50s, 1948-2003 (Box 88)
  - "The Sound of Music", 1968-1998; 2 (Box 88)
  - Crouse, Anna, transcript, 1997 (Box 88)
  - Hammerstein, undated (Box 88)
  - "The Rogues", 1964 (Box 88)
  - "The Park Avenue Farmer", undated (Box 88)
  - "The Farmer from 56th Street", 1964 August (Box 88)
  - "The Farmer from Palermo", undated (Box 88)
  - The Polidoro picture script, undated (Box 88)
  - "The Moving Picture Boys", 1978, undated; 3 (Box 89)
  - Assorted clippings, circa 1971 (Box 89)
  - Statistics, undated (Box 89)
  - Audiocassettes
    - "Celeste Holm talks and sings Oklahoma !", undated; 1 (Box 90, Item barcode 39002109974403)
    - Oklahoma!, 1980; 1 (Box 90)
      This audiocassette is a commercial tape. It has not been digitized.
    - " Oklahoma ! Witnesses speak, Elaine Steinbeck", undated; 1 (Box 90, Item barcode 39002109974411)
    - "Tony Thomas interviews: Rodgers and Hammerstein", 1972 March 26; 1 (Box 90, Item barcode 39002109974429)
      Annotation on the audiocassette reads: "No Oklahoma comments but you might like to listen". Notes also describe Agnes DeMille comments on casting for Oklahoma! made at Rodgers' tribute at Imperial Theater in New York.
    - "Memo from Max Wilk: Oklahoma! ", undated; 1 (Box 90, Item barcode 39002109974437)
    - "In conversation with Arnold Michaels: Rogers and Hammerstein", undated; 1 (Box 90, Item barcode 39002109974445)
    - "Rodgers and Hammerstein: oral histories", 1957; 1 (Box 90, Item barcode 39002109974452)
      Arnold Michaelis [interview?] with Oscar Hammerstein re. "Oklahoma!" Dick Rodgers re. "Oklahoma!"
    - "Rodgers", undated; 1 (Box 90, Item barcode 39002109974460)
    - "Heller Markel. Wilk - re. TV series. Conversation: Live from New York", 1981 March 11; 1 (Box 90, Item barcode 39002109974478)
  - Computer media
    - "Max Wilk, These are the jokes", undated; 1 computer disk
      - FILE NAME MWPLAY.O20 M.WILK THESE ARE THE JOKES MS/DOS WORDSTAR NOT46-63.RB PRINTALL.RB INVOICE, 2004-ycal-0512-h-0001; 1 (Box 91)
        Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Sound of Genius", undated
      - SOUND OF GENIUS MAX WILK .MAX, 2004-ycal-0512-h-0002; 1 (Box 91)
    - "Mr. Williams and Miss Wood", 1989 August 2
      - MR WILLIAMS AND MISS WOOD 2nd version. Aug2.1989. Santa Fe., 2004-ycal-0512-h-0003; 1 (Box 91)
    - "Wilk, Wordperfect", undated
      - WILK - Wordperfect 4.2, 2004-ycal-0512-h-0004; 1 (Box 91)
  - Record albums
    - "These are transcriptions of Word War II programs made to send out to the home people by the Air Force. Rare! (by me [Wilk] as a writer)", 1943-1945; 6 12" record albums (Box 92 (Record album storage))
      Resricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Oversize
    - Sunday Times Magazine, 1970 September 20 (Box 93 (Oversize))
    - Sunday Times Magazine, 1970 September 27 (Box 93 (Oversize))
    - Sunday Times Magazine, 1970 October 11 (Box 93 (Oversize))
    - Sunday Times Magazine, 1970 October 16 (Box 93 (Oversize))
    - Sunday Times Magazine, 1970 October 25 (Box 93 (Oversize))
    - Sunday Times Magazine, 1970 November 8 (Box 93 (Oversize))
    - Various book reviews, 1970-1971 (Box 93 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook of clippings for "Death Watch," "Brass Section", 1946-1957 (Box 94 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook of clippings for "Cloud Seven," "The Fabulous Fifties", 1957-1959 (Box 95 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook of clippings for "Don't Raise the Bridge", 1960-1961 (Box 96 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook of clippings for "Rich is Better", 1962 (Box 97 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook of clippings for "Help! Help! Help!", 1963-1964 (Box 98 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook of clippings for "The Beard," "Dirty Minds Never Sleep," "One of Our Brains is Draining," "The Yellow Submarine", 1965-1969 (Box 99 (Oversize))
    - T. I. T. A. 35th Anniversary Reunion photograph, undated (Box 100 (Oversize))
    - "Jonathan Winters: A Tree in South Boston," poster, 1986 Janurary 8 (Box 100 (Oversize))
      Inscribed to Barbara, January 8 '86
    - Window cards: Cloud 7, Harvey, The Hottentot, Kiss and Tell, Mr. President, Oh Boy!, Springtime for Henry, This is Actors Fund Week, What a Day, You Never Know, 1983-1985, undated; 11 (Box 100 (Oversize))
- 2008 Acquisitions, 1904-2007; 36; 0.21; (1 box)
  - "If the Beatles Had Only Said Yes!," typescript, list of tape transcriptions, 1 clipping, 1970-2007, undated (Box 101)
  - 1 black and white photograph of Marion Moore and Carl Van Vechten, with manuscript notes on verso by Carl Van Vechten and inscription to Max [Wilk] from "Donald;" with 1 clipping (photocopy), [1904?] undated (Box 101)
- February 2009 Acquisition, 1735-2007; 37; 20.02; (19 boxes) + 1 record album storage
  Arrangement
  Arranged by type of material.
  Boxes 107-116 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Writings
    - 100th Anniversary Tribute to Perelman. Nash, Duke & Hirschfeld, 2004 October; 2 (Box 102)
    - Advertising Sketch "Small Wonder", 1948 June (Box 102)
    - "And Now For The Weather", 1953 (Box 102)
    - "And Then I Wrote," by Irving Caesar and Max Wilk, 1952 (Box 102)
    - "Ask Me No Questions", 1952 (Box 102)
    - "The Author Met His Match", 1938, 1946 (Box 102)
    - Back up with new organizaton,"Schmucks", 2003; 7 (Box 102)
    - "The Bocciagalupi Soccer Team", undated (Box 102)
    - "The Brass Section", 1955-1996; 2 (Box 102)
    - "Buster and Ed", undated (Box 102)
    - "Bypass", 1990 (Box 102)
    - "Candy is Dandy: an Evening of Ogden Nash Lyrics and Verses," arranged by Max Wilk, 1993-1994; 5 (Box 102)
    - "Caitlin and the Indians" (photocopy), undated (Box 102)
    - "Child's Play," by Max Wilk and Ted Murkland, undated (Box 102)
    - Coward in Vegas, 1997, undated (Box 102)
    - "Dame Fortune", 1948 February 10 (Box 102)
    - "Danny Boy", 1953-1996 (Box 102)
    - "Dear Dorothy", 1956 (Box 103)
    - "Dear Old London", 1996 (Box 103)
    - "A Dirty Mind Never Sleeps", 1969 (Box 103)
    - "Don and Ella", 1996, undated; 2 (Box 103)
    - "Down the Rabbit Hole," by Willy Holtzmann and Max Wilk, 1995 (Box 103)
    - "Entering Farrellville", 1952 (Box 103)
    - "The Funniest Wasp", 1994 May (Box 103)
    - "Gifted", 1958 (Box 103)
    - "Glad to See You", 1942-1943 (Box 103)
    - "Have a Heart," by Max Wilk and Ted Murkland, 1949-1996 (Box 103)
    - "Heart To Heart", 1949 (Box 103)
    - "Help", undated (Box 103)
    - "I Can Explain Everything", undated (Box 103)
    - An idea for a television series, 1959 October 15 (Box 103)
    - "I Love Miss Cathcart, Too!", 1954 (Box 103)
    - "I Love My Wife," by Sgt. Hal Kanter [Max Wilk], 1944 (Box 103)
    - "I Should Have My Head Examined", 1953 (Box 103)
    - "I Thought I'd Die", 1951 (Box 103)
    - "Last Summer", 1954 (Box 103)
    - "The Last Supper", 1954 (Box 103)
    - "Leave Us Face It", undated (Box 103)
    - "Mad Dogs and English Men," by Max Wilk and Willy Holtzman, 1999 (Box 103)
    - "Mad Money," by Max Wilk and Lee Rogow, 1955-1956 (Box 103)
    - "Man Walks Alone", undated (Box 103)
    - "Manhattan at Midnight", undated (Box 103)
    - Military Training Manuals, 1943-1945 (Box 103)
    - "Mr. Williams and Miss Wood," by Audrey Wood and Max Wilk, 1989 (Box 103)
    - "Mrs. Jackson's Jewel", 1954 (Box 103)
    - "The National Park: Lessons in Diversity", 2002 (Box 103)
    - "A note on the type in which this work was originally composed", 1996 March (Box 103)
    - "Oh, the Editor and the Author Should Be Friends", 1996 (Box 103)
    - "The Old Oil", 1953 (Box 103)
    - "One in a Thousand", undated (Box 103)
    - "Our Fearless Leader", undated (Box 103)
    - "The Phantom of Brookline", 1952 (Box 103)
    - "Pie-Eyed Piper", 1953 (Box 103)
    - "Red Letter Day", 1953 (Box 103)
    - "Run Scared," outline for TV, 1957 (Box 103)
    - "Slow Burn", 1943 February (Box 103)
    - "So Little Time," by Pvt. Walter Mason [Max Wilk], 1943 (Box 103)
    - "Splitting Image", undated (Box 103)
    - Stock Story: M. M. McBride play, 1944-1946 (Box 103)
    - "Storm Warning Redux", 1996 (Box 103)
    - "That's My Boy," a musical comedy outline by Harold Buchmand and Max Wilk, 1948, undated; 2 (Box 103)
    - "There Are Times When Honesty Is Not the Best Policy," memoir, 2005 April (Box 103)
    - "They're Coming Through the Window", 1953 (Box 104)
    - Three first acts, undated (Box 104)
    - "Tony Bennett and the Indains [sic]", undated (Box 104)
    - "Tunnel of Love", undated (Box 104)
    - Untitled play script, circa 1960 (Box 104)
    - Untitled short story, undated; 2 (Box 104)
    - "A Very Special Delivery", 1953 (Box 104)
    - "What A Day!," by Celeste Holm and Ronnie Graham, produced by Max Wilk, 1959 (Box 104)
    - "The Whitings Carry On," by Leonard Hoffman and Max Wilk, undated (Box 104)
    - "XXXXXXXXXXXX Isn't Everything", 1953 (Box 104)
    - "Yes, Virginia", 1959 (Box 104)
    - "You Beast", 1956 (Box 104)
  - Writings by others
    - "Ave Atque Vale!," by Richard Freeman Leavitt, 1983 September (Box 104)
    - "Once A Year," by Walker Mason, 1943 (Box 104)
    - "Out of the Inkwell," by Richard Fleischer, 2001 (Box 104)
    - "Storm Warning," by Franklyn Coen, 1946 (Box 104)
  - Interview transcripts
    - "1970 et al. Songwriters", circa 1970 (Box 104)
    - Notes and interview transcripts, 1960-1970 (Box 104)
    - Leo Robin and Harry Warren, 1971 (Box 104)
    - Julie Styne and Richard Rogers, 1971 (Box 104)
    - Lee Adams, Sammy Cahn, Margaret Whiting, Harold Rome and Irving Caesar, 1971-1975 (Box 104)
    - Hirschfeld, Al, 1993, undated (Box 104)
  - Printed material
    - 100 Monologues: An Audition Sourcebook From New Dramatists by Laura Harrington, 1989 (Box 105)
    - Clippings, 1985-2005 (Box 105)
    - Cole: Yale, booklet and ticket stub, 1985 (Box 105)
    - Come Into My Parlor by Charles Washburn, 1936 (Box 105)
      Book is inscribed to John Chapman by Charles Washburn
    - "Costume Drama," printout, 2005 (Box 105)
    - Happy Days by Samuel Beckett, 1961 (Box 105)
      Includes a flyer for "A Centenary Tribute to Jule Styne," and a photograph of Albert Einstein.
    - Danny Kaye: The Philharmonia Orchestra of Yale, 1976 (Box 105)
    - The Kennedy Center Honors: Lucille Ball, 1986 (Box 105)
    - The Loyaltonian v. 1 no.6, 1945 May (Box 105)
    - Memoirs of Vidocq: the principle agent of the French police by Eugène François Vidocq. Philadelphia: T B. Peterson and Brothers, 1859 (Box 105)
      Includes a business card inserted into the book block with note, "from Sidney Harmon."
    - Milton Berle, Mr. Television The Museum of Broadcasting, 1985 (Box 105)
      Book is inscribed to Barbara Wilk from Milton Berle. It also includes inserted pages of a Berle interview transcript.
    - On Writing: A Publication of the Writers Guild of America, 2001 June-July (Box 105)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1968 (Box 105)
    - Performing Arts, 1975 September (Box 105)
    - Stage production programs, 1957-1993; 8 (Box 105)
    - Audiocassette list, undated (Box 106)
    - Schmucks With Underwoods by Max Wilk, 2004 (Box 106)
      Book is signed to Patricia Willis from Max Wilk.
    - "Summer of 1929", undated (Box 106)
    - Television U.S.A. 13 Seasons The Museum of Modern Art Film Library, 1962 (Box 106)
    - The Tender Husband, or, the accomplish'd fools: a comedy by Sir Richard Steele. London: Printed for Jacob Tonson in the Strand, 1735 (Box 106)
    - Theatre Arts, 1949 January (Box 106)
    - A Tribute: Burr Tillstrom, pamphlet, 1983 November (Box 106)
    - Written By: The Journal of the Writer's Guild of America West, 1997 September (Box 106)
    - Yale Daily News, 1939-1940 (Box 106)
  - Other papers
    - Addenda, not collated, 1967 (Box 106)
    - Correspondence: Ira Gershwin letters; P. G. Wodehouse letters, 1971-1975 (Box 106)
      Includes photocopies of correspondence from Ira Gershwin, circa 1972, as well as correspondence from P.G. Wodehouse, circa 1975. Also included is an "Oral History Transcript" list, prepared by Max Wilk.
    - Hambleton, T. Edward, undated (Box 106)
    - Hirschfeld, Al, photograph with Max Wilk, 2002 (Box 106)
    - Winters, Jonathan, photograph, signed, 1994 August 14 (Box 106)
    - Notes: Max Wilk, programs et al., undated (Box 106)
    - Notes: Patricia Willis, 2006 (Box 106)
  - Audio recordings
    - Audiocassettes, 1939-2002
      Boxes 107-116 (audiocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - "Box #1: With List ", 1959-2000
        - "Morton DaCosta's Musical Jubilee, Act I, opening night", 1975 November 13; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974486)
          Audiocassette includes performances by Patrice Munsell, Tammy Grimes, Cyril Ritchard, Larry Kert, John Raitt, Lillian Gish, and Dick Shawn
        - "Morton DaCosta's Musical Jubilee, Act II, opening night", live at the St. James Theatre, 1975 November 13; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974494)
          Audiocassette contains performances by Patrice Munsell, Tammy Grimes, Cyril Ritchard, Larry Kert, John Raitt, Lillian Gish, and Dick Shawn
        - "Regina" by (Marc Blitzstein, recording made for him by cast) / Princess Zenobia ballet (R & H), "On Your Toes", Warner Bros., orchestra (for film version), 1939; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974502)
        - "Schwartz/Dietz, Moss Hart's birthday", Arthur Schwartz with Kitty Carlisle, 1959; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974510)
        - "Harold Sack", 1989 January 25; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974528)
        - "Harold Sack", 1989 August 17; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974536)
        - "Irving Caesar, re American songwriting", Lower East Side, NY, 1976 April 14; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974544)
        - "Arthur Mayer", 1978 May 1; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974551)
        - "David Lahm, Westport", 1994 March 23; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974569)
        - "Mary Ellen Barrett & Friends", 1995 March 26; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974577)
          Included on the audiocassette are Wilk, Grossman, and Munroe at Pequot Library
        - "Bill Hammerstein", 1995 October 17; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974585)
        - "Edward Albee's speech, Edith Oliver's Award", 1996 May; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974593)
          Lucille Lortel Award
        - "Bert Williams", undated; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974601)
          A list of contents is included.
          1. The Moon Shines on the Moonshine - 1919
          2. O Death Where is Thy Sting - 1918
          3. It's Nobody's Business
          4. It's Getting So You Can't Trust Nobody
          5. Bring Back Those Wonderful Days - 1919
          6. Everybody Wants a Key to My Cellar
          7. Brother Low Down
          8. Unlucky Blues - 1920
          9. Nobody - 1913
          10. Somebody - 1919
          11. Ten Little Bottles - 1920
          12. I'm Neutral -1925
          13. I'm Gonna Quit Saturday - 1920
          14. My Last Dollar - 1920
          15. Twenty Years (bet. 1906-1911)
          16. You Can't Get Away From It - 1914
        - "Bert Williams", undated; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974619)
        - "Harold Arlen, 'A Sleeping Bee' demo", undated; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974627)
        - "Try This On Your Piano", 1973 November 30; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974635)
        - "Drama Evening: Voices of the 20th Century", 2000 October 30; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002109974643)
        - "Broadway Applauds, Lincoln Center", undated; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104610408)
        - "Al Hirshfeld, Sweet Bye and Bye; S.J. Perelman, Vernon Duke, Ogden Nash, NY", 1993 October 21; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104610416)
        - "Dolores Grey, Sweet Bye And Bye, NY", 1994 March 8; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104610424)
        - "Jazz In the Grand Tradition, Quick Center", first half, 1995 May 6; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104610432)
          Includes Dick Hyman, Derek Smith, Adam Makovicz, and Sir [Roland] Hanna to "Someday My Prince Will Come" and "How High the Moon"
        - "Jazz In the Grand Tradition, Quick Center", second half, 1995 May 6; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104610440)
          Includes Dick Hyman, Derek Smith, Adam Makovicz, Sir Roland Hanna to "Tenderly" and "Satin Doll" encore
        - "Irving Berlin, NBC-TV Special: Lawrence, Gorme, Burnett, Davis", 1978 August 22; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104610457)
        - "Burr Tillstrom/Wilk", 1977 September 29; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104610465)
        - "Tillstrom/Wilk", 1977 September 29; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104610473)
        - "Wm Gordon/Wilk", 1994 April 29; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104610481)
        - "Billy Joe Bigot-Winters, Frankfurt", 1967; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104610499)
        - "Ethel Merman Concert, Carnegie Hall", undated; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104610507)
      - "Box #2: Famous People", 1949-1993
        - "Conversation with Danny Kaye and Sylvia Fine Kaye re: The Kissinger Noodles and Chinese cooking" (1 of 3 audiocassettes), 1974 July 9; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104610515)
        - "Danny Kaye and Max Wilk - Mr. Ho-Kissinger, Noodles / Kaye, Wilk, Sylvia" (2 of 3 audiocassettes), 1974 July 10; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002104610523)